XML was designed with a number of goals in
在设计 XML 时 设计师心中有多个目标
mind. One of the most important for purposes of this
就本课而言 最重要的一点是
class is, it was designed to provide data transfer
设计它的目的是提供不依赖平台的数据转移
that's platform independent. What does that mean? Well the idea
这是什么意思？主要想法就是
here is that you can have a Producer App.
你可以有一个生产者应用
That's written in any programming language on any operating system
它以任何编程语言在任何操作系统上
and any type of hardware. And the consumer app
和任何类型的硬件上编写 还有一个消费者应用
implemented in any other programming language operating system or hardware.
该应用是以任何其它编程语言操作系统或硬件实现的
There is no binding between how the consumer app
消费者应用或生产者应用
or the Producer app is implemented, because they both agree
之间没有任何绑定 因为它们都采用 XML
to speak XML to one another. And of course
和对方通信 当然
in addition to consuming XML from the Producer app, the
除了使用生产者应用发出的 XML 外
consumer, wouId also write XML to the Producer app.
消费者还可以编写 XML 给生产者应用
Another important goal for XML is that it would be
XML 的另一个重要目标是
easy to write programs to read and write XML. The
可方便地编写读写 XML 的程序
designers also wanted a data format that could be validated.
设计师同样还希望数据格式是可以验证的
So in XML, we write a specification for a
那么在 XML 中 我们编写一个针对特定文档类型的规范
particular type of document. And then any specific examples
然后就可以根据该规范
of that document that are produced can be validated
来对所生成的该文档的任何其它示例
against that specification. So BioMed Central has a specification for
进行验证 BioMed Central 对于
the research article format, and any articles that are
研究论文格式有一个规范 所生成的任何论文都要按照该规范
produced are validated against that format to ensure They
进行验证
adhere to the rules for that data model. XML
以确保其符合该数据模型的规则
is designed to be human readable, and as we saw
XML 是为便于人工阅读而设计的
in the example, we can get a pretty good idea
正如我们在例子中看到的 我们一看便可对
of what information is contained with in an XML encoding
XML 编码所含的内容
just by looking at it. And finally, XML is designed
有很直观的了解 最后 XML 也是为
to support a wide variety of applications. We've seen one
支持各种应用而设计的
application of XML, we're going to take a look at
我们已经看到了 XML 的一种应用 接下来
several others. That essentially span a number of different ways
还会看到其它一些应用 这些应用基本上包含了一些方式
in which XML can be applied to exchanging data between
在这些方式中 可运用 XML 来交换应用之间的数据
applications. If you're interested in more information about this data format,
如果大家对这种数据格式有更多兴趣
I encourage you to take a look at the
鼓励大家看看
W3C site. We're going to talk a little bit about what
W3C 网站 我们接下来谈谈
having a standard means. One of the most important benefits
拥有一套标准意味着什么 拥有一套 XML 标准的
of there being an XML standard, is that we have
最大好处就是
robust parsers in most programming languages, Python included. What this
在大多数编程语言中 都有强有力的解析器 包括 Python
means for us as data scientists, is that we get
这对我们这些数据科学家来说 意味着
to focus on our own applications. We don't have to
我们可以专注于自己的应用
worry about writing parsers. For some ad hoc data format.
我们无需为编写一些特定数据格式的解析器操心
Previously each messaging system had its own format
以前 每种消息传递系统都有自己的格式
and all were different which made the type
这些格式各不相同 这使得我们处理的信息类型
of messaging that we do now very messy,
显得非常混乱
complex and expensive to do. If everyone uses the
复杂 而且代价高昂 如果大家都使用相同的语法
same syntax, it makes writing these systems a
编写这些系统的速度就会快很多
lot faster. And much more reliable. Another advantage for
也可靠很多 XML 的另一个优势是
XML is that it's free. Now, that's free
它是免费的 它是免费软件
as in beer but also free from legal encumbrances.
并且也不会有什么法律障碍
It's not a format that any company owns and may change out from under us. XML
其格式并未为任何一家公司所有 我们可以去更改它
information can be manipulated programmatically. So we can
XML 信息可以以编程方式操纵
build databases to support specific types of queries. Or,
我们可以构建数据库来支持特定类型的查询
we can piece together data from different sources
也可以把来自不同来源的数据拼接到一起
or take it apart to be reused in
或者分解为不同部分
different ways. XML documents can also be reliably
以不同方式进行再利用 XML 文档还可以可靠的方式
converted into other formats with no loss of information.
转换为其它格式 而不会有信息丢失
XML lets you separate form, or appearance,
XML 让你可以从内容中隔离出表格或外观
from content. So, your XML file contains
因此 你的 XML 文件包含你的文档信息
your document information, all of your text
你所有的文本
and data and identifies it's structure. Formatting
数据和标识符 并识别其结构
and other processing needs are identified separately
格式设置及其它处理需求是通过样式表
in a Stylesheet or processing system. In
或其它处理系统单独识别的
the BoiMed Central example, it is actually the XML that is transformed into HTML
在 BoiMed Central 的例子中 实际是转换为 HTML 的 XML
for rendering on the website or into PDF for download. Using a Stylesheet.
这样便于在网站上渲染 或者采用样式表和样式表处理系统
And style sheet processing system. The two are combined in output time to
转为 PDF 进行下载 这两者在输出时结合到一起
apply the required formatting to the text of data identified by its structure.
以便将所需的格式设置应用到其结构所识别的数据中的文本
This structure might define location, position, order
该结构可以定义位置、顺序
or any other aspects of the data.
或数据的任何其它方面